Is this your G-Wagon?
Yeah.
What do you do for living out in
Houston, Texas to be able to afford a G-Wagon?
Sorry?
What do you do for living out in Houston, Texas?
Work hard.
What industry are you in?
Football.
What are you doing exactly?
I own a football team.
我的隊伍
Houston Texans.
You own the Houston Texans?
H-Town, baby.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Oh, 12 million.
Let's put it this way.
My company will do 300 million this year.
Excuse me, sir, question for you.
Is this your G-Wagon?
Yes, it is.
And what do you do for
living out here in Houston, Texas
to be able to afford a G-Wagon?
I'm a doctor.
What's been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
Six million dollars a year.
How can somebody own a Ferrari in 2024?
Two simple things.
Number one.
Houston, Texas is the number eight city
in the entire world with the most millionaires.
And today we are in
the wealthiest part of Houston, Texas,
River Oaks, to go around asking multi-millionaires
and billionaires how they became wealthy
and how you can start your path
to becoming financially free in 2024.
So with that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
Excuse me, sir, question for you, sir.
Have you ever been broke before?
Oh, man, I get no interview.
Real quick, real quick.
I started the channel in Austin, Texas
at the University of Texas.
I'm good, bro.
Just two questions on advice for the younger generation.
Yeah, I'm good.
Have a good one, man.
Can't get everybody, man, but like I always say,
every no is a step closer to a yes,
so we're just gonna go
get this next one out here
in Houston, Texas, come on.
Question for you.
Is this your Lamborghini?
Yeah.
Are you a business owner by any chance?
Yeah, I own and went to
find a work for a woman, yes.
Yeah?
Could I interview you real quick?
I go all over the country just asking business owners
their advice to young entrepreneurs.
I have a channel with over five million followers.
Could I ask you just a couple quick questions?
Is that cool?
Well, no, not today.
Just two quick questions then?
Not today, I'm sorry.
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you.
Yes, sir.
Have you ever been broke before?
Oh, God, yeah.
Yeah?
And what do you do for
a living out here in Houston, Texas?
I own a restaurant, Fari, right around the corner.
Restaurant business is very competitive.
What do you do to stand out against 99%
of the hospitality business?
Come on, you're asking secret questions here.
Yeah?
I started the channel in Austin, Texas.
I grew up to five million followers.
Just asking business owners their best advice
to young entrepreneurs.
Could I get just one
or two minutes of your time?
I'm not young, I'm 72 years old.
And I want your advice for the younger generation
of business owners.
I've interviewed Mark Cuban, president of Nike,
CEO of Frito Lake.
Just a couple quick questions.
Be fearless.
Is fear the biggest killer of most businesses
in today's world?
Don't be afraid to fail.
What's the best advice you ever got from a mentor
in terms of money or
how you were able to make
that money work for you?
Don't deal drugs.
Don't deal drugs?
Two quick last ones for you, real quick, sir.
Is that cool?
Is that okay?
Yeah, it was.
Is that fine?
So what kind of restaurants do you own?
I own this restaurant right there, Bari.
It's right across the street, it's Italian.
Across all your businesses,
what's the biggest you ever had in business?
What's the most you made in
a year in terms of revenue?
Oh, 12 million.
12 million dollars?
Okay, last one for you, right here, right here.
How did you scale from seven to eight figures?
It's hard to scale businesses.
What'd you do to go from seven to eight figures?
Just have a good product.
Have a good product?
How did you find a winning product, though?
That's enough.
All right, you guys, so they got the moguls out
in Houston, Texas, but it's very hard to get
a couple minutes of these people's time.
These are very high net worth individuals,
but all you can do is kind of keep trying
and keep going until you find one of those yeses.
And we're gonna drop some great game
in one of these interviews.
We just gotta go find
it and keep it rolling, man.
Come on, is this your G-Wagon?
Yeah.
What do you do for living out in Houston, Texas
to be able to afford a G-Wagon?
Sorry?
What do you do for living out in Houston, Texas?
Work hard.
What industry are you in?
Football.
What are you doing exactly?
I own a football team.
What team?
Houston Texans.
You own the Houston Texans?
H-Town, baby.
And how long have you been a business owner for?
We've had the Texans for 20 plus years.
Over the 20 plus years you've been a business owner,
what's the greatest lesson that you've learned
about entrepreneurship?
Never, never quit.
How did you break into the National Football League, man?
It's very competitive to try to get into that business.
How did you break in
and start a football team?
Where do we have to
be able to own a team?
What did it take?
Oh, well, we were very successful in another business.
What business?
And then sold it, the power industry.
Sold it and then my dad actually bought the Texans
as a franchise expansion back in,
oh two was our first year.
What was the best advice that
you ever got from a mentor?
Conserve your cash.
Now did you have to borrow money
to start and grow businesses or like?
There was leverage involved.
And then opportunities happen,
you hopefully have some cash
you can take advantage of them.
How old are you now?
I am 63, but don't tell anyone.
Are you a professional?
Are you a billionaire?
I haven't added it up.
You probably believe it though.
Any negotiation advice?
Somebody they struggled to close deals in business,
you've negotiated some massive deals.
What's the secret to negotiating?
You wanna do it, but not that bad.
What do you mean by that?
You gotta be able to walk away or what?
You gotta be able to walk away.
At the same time you're
gonna be able to do it.
Absolutely.
Thank you, sir, I appreciate you.
Thank you.
Hard Knocks family, we just interviewed
the owner of the Houston Texans.
That guy is more than likely a billionaire
and we just caught him getting out of the G-Wagon,
going to his appointment at the Rolex store.
But what did he say was
the best advice he'd give to anyone?
Any business owner in today's world, never, ever quit.
Right when people are on the brink of achieving
their greatest dreams and the greatest goals that they have,
they give up right before it all happens.
Never give up on your dreams, guys.
And you can interview people like the owner
of the Houston Texans.
Crazy interview out here in Houston to start the day.
Let's go get this next one, fellas, come on.
Excuse me, sir, question for you.
Have you ever been broke?
Give me five minutes.
I got you.
And then we'll.
Appreciate you, my friend.
Because I'm working and it's a, is it like?
Oh, you're good, man, how you doing?
And I'm not a millionaire.
Oh, okay, cool.
But, so I work at the,
at the jewelry store.
And you'll pass by and somebody will actually
walk in and actually be like, oh, that's a,
Oh, nice, awesome.
Sadly, I'm not a millionaire, yet.
But I'm working at it.
Nice.
So, you never know.
Absolutely.
Have you found a bunch of millionaires in the district?
A couple, man, I don't know, Houston.
I'm from Austin.
There's a lot of money here.
I mean, you know, you'll come
across a bunch, I don't know.
And then maybe it'll help
you get something that goes viral
and then you'll be the millionaire.
If you're not already.
Yes, sir, we're getting there, we're getting there.
Cool.
Yes, sir, what's your name, sir?
Mako.
Mako? Yes.
James.
Nice to meet you.
Hard Knocks Family.
My guy just pulled up in a Ferrari
out here in Houston, Texas.
He's right outside of the Rolex store.
We're gonna go up and see
what he was able to do
to be able to afford
a Ferrari out here in Houston.
Let's go see what he has to say.
Excuse me, sir.
Is this your Ferrari?
Yeah, it is.
What do you do for living out in Houston, Texas
to be able to afford a Ferrari?
I'm an entrepreneur.
And how long have you been a business owner for?
21 years.
And what type of business do you run?
I own a labor force management company.
You can only do so much as one person.
That's right.
How important was it for you learning
how to master delegation, bringing other people
and building teams?
The company will do 300
million this year in revenue, right?
If I were still doing it
all myself, we might do three.
Right?
One guy can only, or
gal, can only do so much.
I don't care how talented you are,
I don't care how hard you work.
You can only do so much.
And you gotta be honest with yourself.
You have weaknesses, right?
That's the truth.
You have strengths and that's great.
You've gotta build a team around you
that are going to cover all those weaknesses
that you've got, help you accentuate
and exaggerate your strengths that you have.
But at the end of the
day, if you don't have a team
that's executing with you and on your behalf,
number one, you're gonna work
for the rest of your life.
So I wouldn't call you an entrepreneur,
I would say you're self-employed.
You're not building a company that's gonna grow
and scale and live beyond you.
You're not building anything lasting.
All you did was create a job.
And by the way, that's great.
I know some people that
do a very, very good job
and they have a very nice living doing just that.
But if you're gonna be an entrepreneur,
if you're really gonna build a business,
which I think is create something
that lives beyond any one person,
you gotta know how to motivate
and inspire a team around you.
In other words, you gotta stop
being an employee entrepreneur.
A lot of people, they work in the business.
Yeah, yeah.
No, you need to be working on the business.
As a multiple nine-figure entrepreneur,
what's been the best financial advice
that you've ever received throughout your career?
Don't be fooled by all the Ferraris
and the paddocks and all that BS.
Don't be fooled by that.
Know something, every dollar that a company spends
must have an ROI attached to it.
If you're doing that, then you can take
and spoil yourself a little bit of that money.
But as far as the business runs financially,
no dollar should ever be spent inside of a business
that does not, you cannot directly calculate
the ROI to that business.
And have you ever been broke before?
I think every entrepreneur
has been broke before, 100%.
By the way, there was a point in time,
I'll never forget this,
I'd actually made about $3 million a year.
I think I was 28 years old.
Every dollar that I'd made
had to stay in the company,
but yet I had to
pay income taxes on that money.
So I owed like $950,000
in income taxes on that money.
And I had like $10,000 in
the bank, in my personal account.
So yeah, I was definitely broke growing up, for sure.
And I'm proud of that because
I think had I not gone
through that path and growing up that way,
I don't think I would have
understood people the way I do.
I don't think I would have had the grit, desire,
and perseverance that I have today.
So that's easy to talk about.
What people don't really understand is that
you can make a lot of
money as an entrepreneur on paper
and be broke financially, personally,
because every dollar that you're making,
if you're doing the right thing,
it's got to stay in the
company to be able to grow it.
It takes money to make money, like I said.
How did you get the money to start your business?
Like, did you have a
lot of money when you started?
No, no, we had no money.
So you have to beg, borrow, and steal
when you're starting it out, right?
Especially when you have no money.
So, I mean, you're literally winging it,
robbing from Paul to pay Peter, trying to grow it,
trying to find just enough money to cover your expenses
to get through each month
and then build up those relationships.
You're trying to earn.
So, I mean, we had
to take out high interest loans.
I call it loan shark money back then,
but it was like, you know, you're factoring your invoices.
It's like 21% interest rate.
It's horrible.
It's absolutely horrible.
But I'm actually really glad I did it that way.
I started out that way
and I had to pay those absurd interest rates
because it forced me to have the discipline
to not take the money out of the business.
So every week that the company made profit,
I'd leave that profit in.
That means next week, that's a little bit less
I had to borrow and a little bit less
and a little bit less.
And then you look up, you
know, 18 months, two years later,
now you're borrowing very, very little
on what I call the loan shark.
You know, loan shark money, right?
But the best part is
you've built up your retained earnings.
You've built up your balance sheet.
Now you can go to a bank,
get a traditional line of credit at six or 8%,
whatever's going on.
And now you go from
21% interest on your capital needs
to six or eight.
You've probably got an extra 20, $25,000 a month,
right back to your bottom line.
Yeah, that's amazing.
You know, they don't teach that in school, right?
No, they don't teach any of this in school.
That's the problem.
That is the big problem.
I think it's one of
the biggest problems in this country
is that we're not teaching the things
that are really going to change people's lives
and empower them to, listen,
everybody's got goals and aspirations.
Everybody does.
Very, very few people have the discipline
and perseverance it takes to achieve them.
But when you get past even those things, listen,
I had learned these things the hard way.
I wish this would have been taught in school,
basic business finance, right?
Had this been taught,
I probably would have been a millionaire,
probably closer to 24, 25 years old.
Listen, I got there at 28.
I'm happy about that.
But I think, yeah, I think it could have happened.
Well, I know.
I know it would have happened much sooner
had I understood those principles of business.
Last one for you, 45 today,
for a young 20 year
old kid watching this right now,
they want to own a house.
They want to own a Ferrari in today's world.
This is a lot of people's dream car
you're sitting in right now.
Yeah, sure.
How can somebody own a Ferrari in 2024?
Two simple things.
Number one, find something you're truly passionate about.
Everything else after that is secondary.
You've got to be passionate about it.
That's number one.
Number two, you just don't ever quit.
I tell people all the time,
I wasn't always the smartest person in the room.
I was just the SOB that refused to quit.
I love it.
Thank you so much for your time.
My pleasure, man.
I appreciate you, brother.
Absolutely.
Have a great day.
Hard Knocks family,
we're on the way to go
get our next interview right now,
but I've got a very special announcement to make.
Last week, we just launched
our official entrepreneur community,
otherwise known as the School of Mentors.
Inside of this community,
I'm hosting a live call every single week
with the multimillionaires and billionaires
that you see us interview every week on the channel.
You'll be able to ask them questions about your career,
your life, and your business.
You're also going to get access to exclusive masterclasses
I've been filming with the most successful business owners
in the entire world.
You do not want to
miss out on any of this,
so click the link down
in the description of this video
to join the School of Mentors today.
We'll see you on the inside,
but with that being said,
let's go get this next interview.
Excuse me, sir, question for you.
Is this your G-Wagon?
Yes, it is.
And what do you do for
living out here in Houston, Texas
to be able to afford a G-Wagon?
I'm a doctor.
How long have you been a doctor for?
30 years.
What type of medicine do you practice in?
I'm a lung specialist, an ICU specialist.
Do you own your own practice?
Yes, I do.
Over these 30 years,
especially as a business owner,
what's been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
Well, the business is different than the medicine.
So medicine is probably six, 700,000.
How about for the business?
The business is a big business,
so that's $6 million a year.
$6 million.
Was it all worth it, going through all that school?
Absolutely.
Why is that?
I always tell my kids, if I go back,
I wouldn't change a thing.
What did you have to sacrifice on the way, though?
Time and time with my wife and the kids.
But it's worth it.
The kids are good.
How old are you today?
I'm 54 years of age.
For people that are pursuing medicine,
what's the most common mistake
that you see new doctors make?
I think the doctor's biggest mistake,
they don't learn the business of medicine.
I don't mean it as a money, but meaning
when you are taking care of patients,
you want to do it the most efficient way.
And if you're in private practice,
you want to do it so you could
stay afloat because if you don't do the right job,
money is not important to doctors,
but money is what sinks a lot of practices.
So you're going to have to balance that out.
You're never after the money, but you also,
if you have a practice, private practice,
you need to be in and
you need to have that niche
and to stay afloat because unfortunately,
you guys don't know this, as a young generation,
medicine pays less and less for doctors,
which we accommodate that, but
then you have to stay afloat.
I have like 300 employees that
I have to pay them payroll
at the end of every month.
So yeah.
Yes, doctors think I could be employed
and that's the end of it.
But if you go into private practice,
you really have to work
harder and have that business mind.
So my one advice is learn business early on,
not because you're after money or you want more money
or how to squeeze the system.
No, to the contrary, how to give good service
to your patients, but stay
afloat and not worry about that.
Because why doctors in general get paid higher than average
is because you don't want your doctors to be worried
about money, you want to worry about you
and how to get you better.
So there's a balance right there.
You don't want to make so much money
and people think they're doing something not right
or too little money
that they worry about making money to survive.
I love it.
Thank you, sir.
I appreciate you.
That's a wrap on today's video, you guys.
Houston, Texas just went crazy,
but I want you to
like and subscribe for amazing content
we've got coming very soon
at the School of Hard Knocks.
And as I mentioned earlier,
we just launched our official entrepreneur community
to connect you guys directly with the millionaires
and the billionaires that we interview every single week.
So that way you guys can also learn directly
from these people and start growing in your career
and your businesses.
So to join this community,
click the link down in the description below
and join the School of Mentors today.
You do not want to
miss out on any of this.
So we can't wait to see you on the inside.
And with that being said,
we'll see you guys in the next video.